Curriculum Vitae VALENTIN NICULA

PERSONAL INFORMATION

VALENTIN CONSTANTIN NICULA



- Benalmadena, Spain
- +34642613511
- constantin.nicula@gmail.com
- www.facebook.com/Valentin.Nicula Skype: constantin.nicula@gmail.com

Sex Male | Date of birth 29/04/1986 | Nationality Romanian

PERSONAL STATEMENT

With more then 5 years experience in Sales and Customer Representative, 2 years in a very dynamic transport company and some years dedicated to Tourism, I can handle just about any job related to this fields. I am a hardworking, reliable and serious individual, very fast learner and enthusiastic about achieving goals. C1 Cambridge degree for English and B2 Cervantes for Spanish even though I have grown to a C1 in the meantime.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Enero 2019 - present

Traffic & Fleet Manager

(5* Transfer company in Costa del Sol)

- Organizing day to day activity which included generating working shifts to cover all our contracted services, selecting the proper vehicles for them, assigning the shifts to the drivers according to their qualifications, making sure all service are doable with a margin of error also, considering worst case scenarios and having back up changes in mind
- Managing day to day changes in our schedule due to clients petition
- Tracking flights, keeping record of all delays, handling all last minute adjustments
- Dealing with all suppliers regarding parts, cleaning products, maintenance products for the cars and garage
- Making sure all vehicles are in their top condition, with all revisions made in time, ITV's, tacographs are in order
- Answering phones and resolving clients requests, giving out prices, putting in new bookings, checking future bookings
- · Reviewing all drivers activity, keeping track of their driving times, brakes, days off, vacations
- Outsourcing services that we cannot cover, making sure the partners will follow our working protocol so all our services are provided at the same level of quality
- Always looking for better suppliers and negotiating service ratios, gps tracking systems, spare parts, 3rd party services
- · Posting ads and interviewing new drivers and personnel for the traffic department

April. 2016 - Dec. 2018

Tour Guide & Vacation Rep in Costa del Sol

Self Employed, collaborator with different travel agencies

- · Handled all groups arriving in Costa del Sol to spend their vacation or bound for Morocco
- Organizing transfer to hotel, checking rooming list, organizing dinners, out of schedule meals, assuring every customer is well settled in.
- Organizing info meetings and doing out the sales for extra activities
- · Organize the activities from transport to local guides and lunches at local restaurants
- Playing a big role in informing the groups about destination, passing by monuments, schedule, entrances and whatever they must new when visiting a new destination
- Doing the panoramic tour and then a walking tour to get to know the city and sometimes doing a guided tour of the main monuments
- Keeping track of all receipts, complaints, special requests and reporting with the agency.

Curriculum Vitae VALENTIN NICULA

Oct. 2013 - Nov. 2015

Reservation Agent (1y) & Tour Manager (1y)

Romania Car Transfers, Bucharest (www.romaniacartransfers.com)

- First I was responsible for maintaining the website, create itineraries, constantly check the market & competition, manage all bookings & respond to all customer requests.
- Also, I was responsible to handle all special requests, help with creating tailor made tours, arrange pick-ups, handle the communication with all suppliers
- As a Tour Manager I handled all tourists coming to visit our country, I drove them around to all the
 places of their interest but also gave suggestions of unspoiled places, I created unique itineraries
 and was always on the lookout to provide a unique experience.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING March.2015 – May.2015

Travel Agent Internship @ TUI Travel

TUI Travel Centre, Bucharest, Romania (http://www.tui-travelcenter.ro/)

- I did this internship in order to acquire more knowledge about the tourism industry, to find out how a
 top agency handled her clients and respond to requests, to improve my skills with all travel software
 used worldwide
- After this internship I can say with confidence that I have no issue in dealing with walking in clients, provide valuable information according to customer's request, reading a situation and get the most out of it.
- Can provide letter of recommendation for TUI's Travel Centre CEO

Jan. 2010 - Oct. 2013

Sales Agent & Account Manager

Inkorporate Print, Bucharest

- Cold calling for new clients
- Developing new business relations with important companies on the market
- Searching for new opportunities to enlarge my portfolio
- Presenting our products and services to clients
- Very strong counselling skills
- Follow-up all requests
- Consult with DTP department regarding the documents of the client
 Finding the best solution for the client
- Verifying all orders in the production department, making sure that they were printed correctly and that the delivery will be on time

Jan. 2009 - Nov. 2009

Real Estate Agent

Postbank Real Estate divison, Bucharest

- Managed some of the banks properties
- Listing, sales & renting of the properties
- Organizing auctions and also actions to recover unpaid properties
- Presenting properties to interested clients, corporate or non juridical persons

OCT. 2014 – January 2018

Travel Guide & Tourism Agent @ ANAT

National Association of Travel Agencies in Romania, Bucharest (http://www.anat.ro/en/)

- Did this training in order to gain more knowledge about the tourism industry. It was a complete
 programme in which we studied all parts of the tourism industry, from airline travel to train / bus
 travel, communication, niche businesses, history, art, guiding, AMADEUS training, selling strategies,
 follow up strategies, how to provide a good service before & after sale.
- I can strongly admit that I can hold a presentation in front of a group, I can create an itinerary from scratch, I can deal with all problems that might appear on the way and I will be appreciated by my tourists. Also, I graduated the course with an A(10).

Oct. 2004 – July 2008

Public & European Administration specialist

SNSPA, (National School of Political and Administration Studies), Bucharest (http://www.snspa.ro/)

• I got a paid scholarship to study at this top rated University, managed to get admitted in the 3rd year to European Administration but after some internships in the local administration offices I found out that this domain is not as challenging as I thought. Graduated with an A-.

Curriculum Vitae VALENTIN NICULA

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)

Romanian

Other language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
C1	C2	B2	B2	C1

Spanish

English

Levels: A1/A2: Basic user - B1/B2: Independent user - C1/C2 Proficient user

Communication skills

- Good communication & situation handling skills gained through my experience as sales agent

Organisational skills

I can say that organisation & situation assessment are my main skills, after practicing my tour manager activity and had been put in a lot of situation that I handled with care. Also Working as a traffic mananger in my last position proved that I can handle stress situations very well, always finding the best solutions on all sides in a timely manner.

Job-related skills

• I am also a very positive person, clever, hardworking, business wise, love to work with customers.

Digital competence

SELF-ASSESSMENT						
Information processing	Communication	Content creation	Safety	Problem solving		
Proficient User	Proficient User	Independent User	Proficient User	Independent User		

Levels: Basic user - Independent user - Proficient user

ICT-certificate(s)

- good command of office suite (while i was studying for European Administration, a main request for graduation was to obtain an ECDL Certificate)
- good knowledge of Adobe Suite gained while working in the printing industry and spending a lot of time in DTP department

Other skills

- SAP software, Corel XDraw, Adobe Suite, ECDL, Amadeus

Driving licence

B + AM

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Courses & Certifications

- Travel Agent & Guide Certification , ANC, 2015
- Tourism Guide in Andalucia, Junta de Andalucia, 2019
- Cambridge Certificate C1 advanced, University of Cambridge, 2017

Volunteer work

- Diploma de Espanol B2, Instituto Cervantes, 2018
- Guide @Bucharest Greeters , http://bucharestgreeters.ro/